<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CanDo OT</title>
    <link>http://www.cando-ot.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on CanDo OT</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright CanDo Occupational Therapy - 2016</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2016 14:40:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.cando-ot.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Returning to work after brain injury</title>
      <link>http://www.cando-ot.com/post/returning-to-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2016 14:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.cando-ot.com/post/returning-to-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our second blog post is going to focus on returning to work after mild to moderate brain injury. Now obviously return to work happens at different times depending on the severity of the brain injury, and the time elapsed since the original injury. But generally speaking, the process itself and the things you need to consider before returning to work are fairly similar. Sometimes return to paid employment is not possible at all, and in those cases it is can be beneficial to try and find another meaningful and productive activity that you or your loved one can engage in, in place of work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first and most important thing that you need to do is to inform your employer that you have experienced a brain injury. Keeping in touch during the recovery period can help to foster your employer’s understanding of your injury and potential difficulties that you may face on your return to work. There may be opportunities for you to visit your workplace in a non-working capacity for meetings with your employer, and this can help to de-stigmatise your injury for others, and reduce your personal anxiety about physically returning to the workplace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As occupational therapists, the process that we would employ when considering your return to work is to break down the components of the job that you do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We look at the physical demands placed upon you – do you spend the majority of your day standing or seated? Do you have any lifting to do? Is there a requirement for advanced motor skills, for example, those required to operate heavy machinery or production lines?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also look at the cognitive demands of the job. Is there a need for sustained concentration, or adaptive concentration where you need to be able to switch tasks quickly and effectively, such as when working as a teacher or childcare worker? Is there a requirement for you to have fast and accurate information processing, such as in accountancy or a reception job where you are directing people?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We consider social and communication skills, particularly in the context of brain injury. Do you need to communicate with individuals face to face, over the telephone, in writing? Is there a need for you to have advanced communication skills, such as those required when discussing a complex problem, for example, as an engineer?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We would analyse every element of the job that you do and then consider these in the context of your brain injury, in order to establish what rehabilitation, grading or adjustment is required to get you back to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of adjustments to paid work, there are many that can be made. In some cases, return to work is just not possible, particularly if you are in a job where the lasting effects of your brain injury could cause harm to others. An example of this would be as a heavy goods vehicle operator. But in most cases of mild brain injury, graded return to work is an option, as are reasonable adjustments such as more frequent rest breaks, or adaptation to the specific activities that your job includes. Rehabilitation can help here whilst the adjustments are being made – your occupational therapist can identify the specific area of the task that you are struggling with, and work with you to improve the motor or cognitive skill associated with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Returning to work can be challenging in the early stages, but generally rewarding and extremely beneficial to the recovery process in the long term. Indeed, many of the issues seen after mild brain injury, in particular, are compounded by a lack of productive occupation and structure in an individual’s day. Work gives us that chance to be productive, it encourages a regular routine, and it provides opportunities for social communication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Headway is a great charitable organisation that supports individuals after brain injury. Some links to relevant areas of their website follows. Thanks for reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.headway.org.uk/about-brain-injury/individuals/practical-issues/returning-to-work/&#34;&gt;www.headway.org.uk/about-brain-injury/individuals/practical-issues/returning-to-work&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.headway.org.uk/media/2818/returning-to-work-after-brain-injury.pdf&#34;&gt;www.headway.org.uk/media/2818/returning-to-work-after-brain-injury.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.headway.org.uk/news/national-news/6-strategies-for-getting-back-to-work-after-brain-injury/&#34;&gt;www.headway.org.uk/news/national-news/6-strategies-for-getting-back-to-work-after-brain-injury/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to CanDo</title>
      <link>http://www.cando-ot.com/post/resource/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 20:22:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.cando-ot.com/post/resource/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi, and welcome to CanDo Occupational Therapy’s blog! Carolyn and I are aiming to make this website somewhere that people can come for free advice and ideas on how to help their loved one, as well as a place where you can find out about what services CanDo can offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So to start the blog off, I thought I’d post a little activity that parents can do with their children that will help to develop their fine motor function in readiness for writing and other important school skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All you need is a colander and some pipe cleaners. I cut them in half so that they don’t bend when they are placed, and they are a little easier to pick up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;img/colander.png&#34; alt=&#34;Colander&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This activity is a great precursor to threading, which can be a difficult skill for little ones to master, especially if their motor skills are already delayed. Picking up the pipe cleaners helps to develop a pincer grasp, and strengthens the tiny muscles in the hand that are used for writing later on. It’s also good for concentration, learning colours, and hand eye coordination. You can even build counting in to it for older children. You can make the activity more difficult by making the pipe cleaners even shorter, and posting them through the holes of the colander.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A short and sweet activity for the first post, but expect more from CanDo very soon!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clare&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>http://www.cando-ot.com/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 10:38:03 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.cando-ot.com/resources/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here are some resources. as sa dsa d as as d sa d s&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://www.cando-ot.com/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2016 20:38:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.cando-ot.com/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CanDo OT&lt;/strong&gt; is an exciting new partnership between two experienced occupational therapists, who share a positive, client centred and goal oriented approach to improving function and quality of life in individuals with neurological problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carolyn and Clare are a pair of occupational therapists who are passionate about maximising independence for people with neurological impairments. With over 40 years of experience between them, Carolyn and Clare have worked in both the public and private sector designing, delivering and overseeing occupational therapy programmes with individuals of all ages.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Team</title>
      <link>http://www.cando-ot.com/team/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2016 20:38:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.cando-ot.com/team/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clare&lt;/strong&gt; qualified as an occupational therapist in 2003, and spent the first 9 years of her career in an NHS hospital renowned for its neurology services. She has worked with both adults and children as a specialist occupational therapist, and in leadership roles in the public and private sector. Clare particularly enjoys working in neuro, where she feels best able to use her occupational therapy skills to maximise individuals&amp;rsquo; independence, and work in a client-centred way. Her experience includes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The rehabilitation and management of brain injuries in both adults and children&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The rehabilitation and management of complex neurological conditions, for example, Guillain Barre syndrome, multiple sclerosis, motor neurone disease&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assessment and treatment of sensory processing difficulties in children&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clare is halfway through her Masters degree in Advanced Occupational Therapy. She is passionate about learning and is always looking for new ways to improve her practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clare is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Registered with the Health and Care Professions Council: OT36654&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A full professional member of the BAOT&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Member of BAOT special interest section for Children, Young People and Families&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Member of BAOT special interest section for Private Practice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Carolyn&lt;/strong&gt; graduated as an occupational therapist from the college of Ripon and York St John in 1988.  She quickly realised her passion for neurology and specialised, now having over 20 years experience with various neurological conditions including: brain injury (physical and cognitive dysfunction, behavioural management and low arousal), stroke and long term neurological conditions. She is also an experienced clinical team leader in both the public and private sectors, training and supporting staff and carers and has set up services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carolyn is continually updating her skills, she completed a post graduate study on apraxia to obtain her MPhil and regularly attends courses, conferences and reads articles to ensure best practise. She is a also a committee member of the local OT specialist interest group in neurology, which looks specifically at the training needs for OT’s within the region.
Carolyn is passionate about her job; her aim is to ensure that clients reach their highest level of independence by making the goals client specific and the activities and interventions purposeful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carolyn is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A full professional member of the BAOT&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Registered with the Health and Care Professions Council&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Member of the OT special interest section for Neurological Practice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Member of the OT special interest for Private Practice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>http://www.cando-ot.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2016 20:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.cando-ot.com/contact/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you feel you need to speak to someone urgently, please call and leave a message on the following number:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clare: 07479 480531&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or, fill out the form below and we will try to get back to you within 24 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problem</title>
      <link>http://www.cando-ot.com/404/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2016 20:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.cando-ot.com/404/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Oh, no, sorry.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What we can offer</title>
      <link>http://www.cando-ot.com/what/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2016 20:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.cando-ot.com/what/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We can provide an individualised, specialist occupational therapy programme for adults and children with all types of neurological impairment. We offer all or part of the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assessment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design and delivery of a tailor made rehabilitation programme&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Equipment and wheelchair assessment and advice on purchase&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;24 hour postural management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assessment and treatment for individuals in low arousal - SMART assessment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Splinting and casting of upper and lower limbs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sensory processing assessment and advice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our philosophy is that the individual is at the centre of the occupational therapy process, and our goals and interventions will aim to optimise and individual’s independence in the areas that are important to them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where we work</title>
      <link>http://www.cando-ot.com/where/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2016 20:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.cando-ot.com/where/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We carry out our sessions with people in the areas in which they function.
This could include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;home&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;work place&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;school&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;community settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are based in Cheshire and can travel reasonable distances within the North West and northern Wales. If you are outside of these areas and still feel you could benefit from our services, please contact us to discuss your requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.google.com/maps/embed?pb=!1m14!1m12!1m3!1d304230.3285792914!2d-2.732935799609381!3d53.43629417154903!2m3!1f0!2f0!3f0!3m2!1i1024!2i768!4f13.1!5e0!3m2!1sen!2suk!4v1455975726175&#34; width=&#34;600&#34; height=&#34;450&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;border:0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>