<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CanDo OT</title>
    <link>http://www.cando-ot.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on CanDo OT</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Code released under the Apache 2.0 license.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2016 20:38:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.cando-ot.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://www.cando-ot.com/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2016 20:38:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.cando-ot.com/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CanDo-OT&lt;/strong&gt; is an exciting new partnership between two experienced occupational therapists, who share a positive, client centred and goal oriented approach to improving function and quality of life in individuals with neurological problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carolyn and Clare are a pair of occupational therapists who are passionate about maximising independence for people with neurological impairments. With over 40 years of experience between them, Carolyn and Clare have worked in both the public and private sector designing, delivering and overseeing occupational therapy programmes with individuals of all ages.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Team</title>
      <link>http://www.cando-ot.com/team/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2016 20:38:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.cando-ot.com/team/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clare&lt;/strong&gt; qualified as an occupational therapist in 2003, and spent the first 9 years of her career in an NHS hospital renowned for its neurology services. She has worked with both adults and children as a specialist occupational therapist, and in leadership roles in the public and private sector. Clare particularly enjoys working in neuro, where she feels best able to use her occupational therapy skills to maximise individuals&amp;rsquo; independence, and work in a client-centred way. Her experience includes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The rehabilitation and management of brain injuries in both adults and children&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The rehabilitation and management of complex neurological conditions, for example, Guillain Barre syndrome, multiple sclerosis, motor neurone disease&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assessment and treatment of sensory processing difficulties in children&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clare is halfway through her Masters degree in Advanced Occupational Therapy. She is passionate about learning and is always looking for new ways to improve her practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clare is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Registered with the Health and Care Professions Council: OT36654&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A full professional member of the BAOT&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Member of BAOT special interest section for Children, Young People and Families&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Member of BAOT special interest section for Private Practice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Carolyn&lt;/strong&gt; graduated as an occupational therapist from the college of Ripon and York St John in 1988.  She quickly realised her passion for neurology and specialised, now having over 20 years experience with various neurological conditions including: brain injury (physical and cognitive dysfunction, behavioural management and low arousal), stroke and long term neurological conditions. She is also an experienced clinical team leader in both the public and private sectors, training and supporting staff and carers and has set up services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carolyn is continually updating her skills, she completed a post graduate study on apraxia to obtain her MPhil and regularly attends courses, conferences and reads articles to ensure best practise. She is a also a committee member of the local OT specialist interest group in neurology, which looks specifically at the training needs for OT’s within the region.
Carolyn is passionate about her job; her aim is to ensure that clients reach their highest level of independence by making the goals client specific and the activities and interventions purposeful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carolyn is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A full professional member of the BAOT&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Registered with the Health and Care Professions Council&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Member of the OT special interest section for Neurological Practice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Member of the OT special interest for Private Practice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>http://www.cando-ot.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2016 20:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.cando-ot.com/contact/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you feel you need to speak to someone urgently, please call and leave a message on either of the following numbers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clare: 07479 480531&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or, fill out the form below and we will try to get back to you within 24 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problem</title>
      <link>http://www.cando-ot.com/404/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2016 20:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.cando-ot.com/404/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Oh, no, sorry.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What we can offer</title>
      <link>http://www.cando-ot.com/what/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2016 20:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.cando-ot.com/what/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We can provide an individualised, specialist occupational therapy programme for adults and children with all types of neurological impairment. We offer all or part of the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assessment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design and delivery of a tailor made rehabilitation programme&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Equipment and wheelchair assessment and advice on purchase&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;24 hour postural management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assessment and treatment for individuals in low arousal - SMART assessment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Splinting and casting of upper and lower limbs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sensory processing assessment and advice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our philosophy is that the individual is at the centre of the occupational therapy process, and our goals and interventions will aim to optimise and individual’s independence in the areas that are important to them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where we work</title>
      <link>http://www.cando-ot.com/where/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2016 20:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.cando-ot.com/where/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We carry out our sessions with people in the areas in which they function.
This could include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;home&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;work place&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;school&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;community settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are based in Cheshire and can travel reasonable distances within the North West and northern Wales. If you are outside of these areas and still feel you could benefit from our services, please contact us to discuss your requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.google.com/maps/embed?pb=!1m14!1m12!1m3!1d304230.3285792914!2d-2.732935799609381!3d53.43629417154903!2m3!1f0!2f0!3f0!3m2!1i1024!2i768!4f13.1!5e0!3m2!1sen!2suk!4v1455975726175&#34; width=&#34;600&#34; height=&#34;450&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;border:0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://www.cando-ot.com/blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.cando-ot.com/blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;date = &amp;ldquo;2016-01-24T20:38:40Z&amp;rdquo;
draft = true
title = &amp;ldquo;blog&amp;rdquo;
menu = &amp;ldquo;main&amp;rdquo;
description = &amp;ldquo;Hello Blog&amp;rdquo;
type = &amp;ldquo;blog&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;+++&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blah blah blah blog &amp;ndash;&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>